

JUAN BAIRES

Front-End Web Developer | Washington, D.C.

I'm a Front-End Developer and musician who writes clean, efficient and reusable code. Driven by the love I have for my family and reinforced by my experience as an Army veteran and father; I am able to adapt and overcome any problem at hand.

CONTACT

www.github.io/juancbaires

(240) - 855 - 5070

juancbaires@gmail.com

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Express
- HandleBars
- ReactJS

- Git
- Github
- Node
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Bootstrap

RELATED EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE

Aug 2018- Sept 2018

- Successfully completed a 13 week full stack web development immersive course, covering a variety of languages and front and back-end frameworks like Javascript, NodeJS, Express, handlebars, ReactJS, MongoDB.
- Built a photo application using ExpressJS, Handlebars and MongoDB
- Built a Trivia web game using HTML, CSS and Vanilla JavaScript.
- Built a Pickup sports application using ReactJS, Express, NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Implemented user authentication using passport, JWT, and Google Firebase.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UNITED STATS ARMY DIESEL TECHNICIAN

Oct 2013- Feb 2017

- Supervised a team of technicians in a maintenance shop for a 250 personnel company with over 200 vehicles in inventory.
- Inspected, repaired and preformed scheduled preventative maintenance on diesel vehicles.
- Maintained an above 90% equipment readiness on 50 vehicles and trailers for 2 years.
- Used schematics and other testing equipment to troubleshoot electrical components in vehicles.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive Aug 2018-Sept 2018

MONTGOMERY COLLEGE

Digital Media and Web Technology Sept -2017-Aug 2018